Having thousands of photos, songs and films available at our fingertips would have seemed amazing just a few decades ago, but how long will these files last for and be available?
几十年前，能够将成千上万的照片、歌曲和电影触手可及似乎令人惊叹，但这些文件能保存多久、又能被访问多久呢？
Could the digitalisation of cultural artefacts now be putting a time limit on our memories?
如今，文化物品的数字化是否正在给我们的记忆设下时间限制？
The materials that phones and computers are made of can decay over time, impacting the data that they store.
手机和电脑的制造材料会随着时间的推移而老化，影响它们存储的数据。
Images can still be seen in faded photographs, but when digital data degrades, it can quickly make it impossible to even open a file.
褪色的照片中仍然可以看到图像，但当数字数据降级时，它可能很快让人连一个文件都打不开。
Also, as formats and devices become obsolete, it may become impossible to read files from previous decades.
此外，随着格式和设备变得过时，很可能无法读取过去几十年的文件。
Storing information in the cloud can also present problems.
将信息存储在云端也可能带来问题。
Large companies can still lose data.
大公司仍然可能丢失数据。
In 2019, social media platform MySpace admitted losing more than 12 years' worth of users' music uploads.
2019年，社交媒体平台MySpace承认丢失了超过12年的用户上传的音乐。
The widespread use of streaming services for music, TV and film means that people no longer own the content that they watch and listen to, they just pay for the right to access it.
音乐、电视和电影流媒体服务的广泛使用意味着人们不再拥有他们观看和收听的内容，他们只是为访问权付费。
If streaming companies decide to remove content, or go out of business, users will lose access.
如果流媒体公司决定移除内容，或者倒闭，用户将失去访问权限。
Licencing rather than buying content is an example of how our behaviour towards digital content has changed.
授权访问而非购买内容是我们改变数字内容行为方式的一个例子。
Another example is that we take far more pictures than people did in the past.
另一个例子是，我们拍摄的照片比过去的人多得多。
This means that, added to the challenge of keeping our data safe, people have to consider what to preserve and what can be discarded.
这意味着，除了保持数据安全的挑战之外，人们还必须考虑哪些需要保存，哪些可以丢弃。
So, what can we do?
那么，我们能做什么呢？
Technology writer Jack Schofield said that "data doesn't really exist unless you have at least two copies of it", so it's important that we keep backup copies of what is important to us – probably more than one.
科技作家杰克·斯科菲尔德说："除非你至少有它的两份副本，否则数据并不真正存在。"因此，对我们重要的东西保留备份副本很重要——可能不止一份。
Academic Paul Royster suggests that we should all take time to consider what content we personally believe is worth saving.
学者保罗·罗伊斯特建议，我们都应该花时间考虑哪些内容是我们个人认为值得保存的。
Perhaps the answer is just to avoid digital altogether.
也许答案就是完全避开数字形式。
Science and Technology writer Chris Baranaiuk calls for a cultural movement towards buying analogue copies of cultural content.
科技作家克里斯·巴拉纽克呼吁发起一场文化运动，转向购买文化内容的模拟副本。